<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"> <id>/</id><title>Forever Noob</title><subtitle>A minimal, portfolio, sidebar, bootstrap Jekyll theme with responsive web design and focuses on text presentation.</subtitle> <updated>2022-04-13T12:29:49+00:00</updated> <author> <name>Forever Noob</name> <uri>/</uri> </author><link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="/feed.xml"/><link rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en-US" href="/"/> <generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.2.0">Jekyll</generator> <rights> © 2022 Forever Noob </rights> <icon>/assets/img/favicons/favicon.ico</icon> <logo>/assets/img/favicons/favicon-96x96.png</logo> <entry><title>Introduction to Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing</title><link href="/posts/vapt/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introduction to Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing" /><published>2021-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2021-05-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/vapt/</id> <content src="/posts/vapt/" /> <author> <name>Forever Noob</name> </author> <category term="Blogging" /> <category term="Vulnerability Assessment" /> <category term="Penetration Testing" /> <summary> Vulnerability assessment (VA) is the intersection between penetration testing and audit. It is used to evaluate whether an IT system is exposed to known vulnerabilities, assign severity levels to identified vulnerabilities, and recommend remmediations or mitigation steps where necessary. Vulnerability assessment is an extension of threat modeling. Vulnerability scanning is the process of ident... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Incidence response.</title><link href="/posts/incidenthandling/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Incidence response." /><published>2021-04-21T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2022-04-13T12:24:19+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/incidenthandling/</id> <content src="/posts/incidenthandling/" /> <author> <name>Forever Noob</name> </author> <category term="Blogging" /> <category term="Incidence Response" /> <summary> It is the process of dealing with an incident to closure. Incidence response plans are written and designed to help organizations prepare for and manage cybersecurity incidents, minimizing business interruption and other losses. An incident response plan is a document that sets out the procedures you will follow in the event of a cyber-attack on your business systems. This includes systems tha... </summary> </entry> <entry><title>Malware Analysis - the basics.</title><link href="/posts/malware/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Malware Analysis - the basics." /><published>2021-03-21T00:00:00+00:00</published> <updated>2022-04-13T12:24:19+00:00</updated> <id>/posts/malware/</id> <content src="/posts/malware/" /> <author> <name>Forever Noob</name> </author> <category term="Blogging" /> <category term="Malware Analysis" /> <summary> To anyone getting into malware analysis, this blog will provide a basic introduction to the subject. Thousands of cyber incidents are occuring on the daily and majority are of the attackers use malware implants to gain entry to an organization. Incidence reports from private companies and government agencies provide a look into how evolved malwares have become. In this blog, I will define some ... </summary> </entry> </feed>
